Guide to the Larry Fagin Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1956-2007; Series I; 14.5
  - Simon, Aaron, 2003-2004 (Box 13, Folder 503-504)
  - Slack, Frances, 1989 (Box 13, Folder 505)
  - Smedman, Lorna, circa 1979 (Box 13, Folder 506)
  - Smith, Alex, 1977 (Box 13, Folder 507)
  - Smith, Dale, 1996, 2003 (Box 13, Folder 508)
  - Smith, Patti, circa 1975 (Box 13, Folder 509)
  - Snow, Richard, undated (Box 13, Folder 510)
  - Sonbert, Warren, 1975-1980 (Box 13, Folder 511)
  - Southgate, Patsy, 1998 (Box 13, Folder 512)
  - Spahr, Juliana, 2000-2000 (Box 13, Folder 513)
  - Spicer, Jack, undated (Box 13, Folder 514)
  - Stanley, George, 1977-2006 (Box 13, Folder 515)
  - Stanton, Johnny, undated (Box 13, Folder 516)
  - Stark-Smith, Nancy, 1987 (Box 13, Folder 517)
  - Stearns, Ethie, 1983-1988 (Box 13, Folder 518)
  - Steiner, Konrad, 2001 (Box 14, Folder 519)
  - Stephenson, Ann, circa 2006 (Box 14, Folder 520)
  - Straub, Peter, 1996 (Box 14, Folder 521)
  - Stull, Richard, 2002, 2007 (Box 14, Folder 522)
  - Suiter, John, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 523)
  - Sullivan, Gary, 1999-2000 (Box 14, Folder 524)
  - Svoboda, Alva, 1977 (Box 14, Folder 525)
  - Szamatowicz, Carol, 1979-2007 (Box 14, Folder 526-529)
  - Teachers & Writers Collaborative, 1991-1996 (Box 14, Folder 530)
  - Temple, John, circa 2003 (Box 14, Folder 531)
  - Thomas, Chantal, 1979-1980 (Box 14, Folder 532)
  - Thomas, Lorenzo, undated (Box 14, Folder 533)
  - Thoreau, Evelyn, circa 2000 (Box 14, Folder 534)
  - Towle, Tony, 1966-2003 (Box 14, Folder 535)
  - Tranter, John, circa 2002 (Box 14, Folder 536)
  - Tremblay, Melissa, 2001-2006 (Box 14, Folder 537)
  - Trungpa, Chogyam, circa 1969-1975 (Box 14, Folder 538)
  - Tupitsyn, Masha, circa 1998 (Box 14, Folder 539)
  - Turk, Marcia, undated (Box 14, Folder 540)
  - Tuttle, Richard, circa 1976 (Box 14, Folder 541)
  - Tysh, Christine, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 542)
  - Ueki, Clara Kumiko, 1992-1994 (Box 14, Folder 543)
  - Valaoritis, Nanos, undated (Box 14, Folder 544)
  - Veitch, Tom, 1969-1997 (Box 14, Folder 545)
  - Violi, Paul, 1977-2007 (Box 14, Folder 546)
  - Vitale, Marianna, 1997-1999 (Box 14, Folder 547)
  - Waits, Tom, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 548)
  - Waldman, Anne, 1969-2003 (Box 14, Folder 549-551)
  - Warhol, Andy, undated (Box 14, Folder 552)
  - Warsh, Lewis, 1968-2000 (Box 14, Folder 553)
  - Wasserman, Jo Ann, 2001-2002 (Box 14, Folder 554)
  - Waters, Jacqueline, 1999-2007 (Box 14, Folder 555)
  - Watson, Craig, 2003 (Box 14, Folder 556)
  - Wehren, Janice, undated (Box 14, Folder 557)
  - Wehrli, Peter, 1976-1978 (Box 14, Folder 558)
  - Weigel, Tom, 2004-2006 (Box 15, Folder 559)
  - Weiner, Hannah, circa 1970 (Box 15, Folder 560)
  - Whalen, Philip, 1968-2003 (Box 15, Folder 561)
  - White, Joseph, circa 1980 (Box 15, Folder 562)
  - Whiting, Nathan, undated (Box 15, Folder 563)
  - Wieners, John, 1984-1990 (Box 15, Folder 564)
  - Williams, Heathcote, 1974 (Box 15, Folder 565)
  - Williams, Johnathan, 1974-1979 (Box 15, Folder 566)
  - Wilson, Robert, circa 1975 (Box 15, Folder 567)
  - Winch, Terence, 1979-2007 (Box 15, Folder 568)
  - Winfield, Alison, 1982, 1998 (Box 15, Folder 569)
  - Winkfield, Trevor, 1969-2007 (Box 15, Folder 570)
  - Witkowski, Annie, 1982 (Box 15, Folder 571)
  - Wolfe, Michael, 1979-1981 (Box 15, Folder 572)
  - Wurtzberger, Lee, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 573)
  - Young, David, 1978-1981 (Box 15, Folder 574)
  - Young, Elizabeth, 1999 (Box 15, Folder 575)
  - Young, Geoff, 1988-2007 (Box 15, Folder 576)
  - Yourgrau, Barry, 1979-1988 (Box 15, Folder 577)
  - Zah, Denee Dubeau, circa 2003 (Box 15, Folder 578)
  - Zapruder, Matthew, 2004 (Box 15, Folder 579)
  - Zavatsky, Bill, 1970-2007 (Box 15, Folder 580)
  - Zurawski, Magdelena, undated (Box 15, Folder 581)
- Writings, 1956-2006; Series II; 2
  Arranged into five subseries: Poems, Collaborative Works, Translations, Essays, and Related Files.
  - Poems
    - "Columns", undated (Box 15, Folder 582-583)
    - "Europe", 1956-1963 (Box 15, Folder 584)
    - "From a Blue Book", circa 1960 (Box 15, Folder 585)
    - "London", 1966-1967 (Box 15, Folder 586)
    - "Neotony", undated (Box 15, Folder 587)
    - "New York", 1967-1968 (Box 15, Folder 588)
    - "Notes from the Cracks in the Floor", circa 1975 (Box 15, Folder 589)
    - "Other", undated (Box 15, Folder 590)
    - "Popeye Laughed" (for Clark Coolidge), 1969 (Box 15, Folder 591)
    - "Procris and Cephalus", 1961 (Box 15, Folder 592)
    - Prose poems, undated (Box 15, Folder 593)
    - "San Francisco", 1962-1965 (Box 15, Folder 594)
    - "San Francisco / New York", 1969 (Box 15, Folder 595)
    - "The Shore", 1968 (Box 15, Folder 596)
    - "Short Story #1", 1969 (Box 15, Folder 597)
    - "Vox", undated (Box 15, Folder 598)
    - Various, 1956-1978 (Box 16, Folder 599-613)
  - Collaborative Works
    - Berkson, Bill - "Yektai's Necktie", undated (Box 16, Folder 614)
    - Berkson, Bill; Fagin, Joan Inglis; Mitchell, Tessie; Padgett, Ron; Warsh, Lewis - "Leon Poems", circa 1973 (Box 16, Folder 615-616)
    - Berkson, Bill; Borregaard, Ebbe; Kyger, Joanne - "Song of Offering", 1972 (Box 16, Folder 617)
    - Berkson, Bill; Carroll, Jim; Veitch, Tom - "Things We'd Like to Do to Anne Waldman (on her birthday April 2, 1970)" (Box 16, Folder 618)
    - Berrigan, Ted - "Plain Speaking Brilliant Manifesto for the Record", undated (Box 16, Folder 619)
    - Clark, Tom - Various, undated (Box 16, Folder 620)
    - Collom, Jack - Various, undated (Box 16, Folder 621)
    - Coolidge, Clark
      - "The Atmosphere of the Other Guy", cover illustrations, photocopies, undated (Box 16, Folder 622)
      - "Do I Hear You Laughing?", undated (Box 16, Folder 623)
      - "for Jean-Luc Godard", 1969 (Box 16, Folder 624)
      - "Great White Coast Jazz Suicides", undated (Box 16, Folder 625)
      - "Guidelines without Realizing", undated (Box 16, Folder 626)
      - "Invisible Walking, Writing Lights", early 1970s (Box 16, Folder 627)
      - "On the Pumice of Morons", circa 1994 (Box 16, Folder 628)
      - Stories, drafts, 1970s (Box 16, Folder 629)
      - "Third Down with God to Go", 1991 (Box 16, Folder 630)
      - "Tonto Lavoris", flyer, undated (Box 16, Folder 631)
      - "Whatever Became of Agnes Mason?", undated (Box 16, Folder 632)
    - Eicher, Amanda - "To Larkspur and Return", undated (Box 17, Folder 633)
    - Gallup, Dick; Hollo, Anselm; Price, Laurie - "Tho you are going...wait a minute", undated (Box 17, Folder 634)
    - Mayers, Bernadette - "Ode to Ted Berrigan", undated (Box 17, Folder 635)
    - Noel, Susan - "Rules for a Birthday", undated (Box 17, Folder 636)
    - Padgett, Ron
      - "Eternal Quest", undated (Box 17, Folder 637)
      - Various, 1999, undated (Box 17, Folder 638)
    - Padgett, Ron; Schneeman, George - "The Poems of George Schneeman", 1968 (Box 17, Folder 639)
    - Pinney, Todd; Stearns, Ethie - "for SKN", 1984 (Box 17, Folder 640)
    - Schneeman, George - "Valentine's Day Poem", 1978 (Box 17, Folder 641)
    - Tuttle, Richard - "Poems by Larry Fagin, Drawings by Richard Tuttle", 1977 (Box 17, Folder 642)
    - Waldman, Anne
      - "On Frank O'Hara", transcription of dialogue, undated (Box 17, Folder 643)
      - Various, 1982, undated (Box 17, Folder 644)
    - Warsh, Lewis - "Home Cooking", undated (Box 17, Folder 645)
    - Winkfield, Trevor - Dig and Delve, 2000-2005 (Box 17, Folder 646-649)
    - Zavatsky, Bill - Various, undated (Box 17, Folder 650)
  - Translations
    - Albert-Birot, Pierre - from Poesie, 1916-1924, circa 1973 (Box 17, Folder 651)
    - Baudelaire, Charles - "Au Lecteur", undated (Box 17, Folder 652)
    - Cocteau, Jean - "La Fin du Potomak" (1939) and "Testament of Orpheus", undated (Box 17, Folder 653)
    - Ganglmair, Siegwald, 1973 (Box 17, Folder 654)
    - Mayakovsky, Vladimir - "An Extraordinary Adventure Which Happened to Me, Vladimir Mayakovsky, in a Summer Cottage", undated (Box 17, Folder 655)
    - Péret, B[enjamin] - "Who Is It", undated (Box 17, Folder 656)
    - Wang Wei - "Deer Park", undated (Box 17, Folder 657)
    - Scheerbarth, Paul - from "Katerpoesie" and prose (co-translated with Evelyn Thureau), circa 1973 (Box 17, Folder 658)
    - Saint-Pol-Roux - Various, undated (Box 17, Folder 659)
  - Essays
    - Draft of memoir for Angel Hair Sleeps with a Boy in My Head, 2000 (Box 17, Folder 660)
    - "New American Poetry 1950-1970" for Encyclopedia of Poetry, undated (Box 17, Folder 661)
    - "Polka Dots and Mean Booms" for Shuffle Boil Magazine, undated (Box 17, Folder 662)
  - Related Files
    Scope and Contents
    Includes press releases, reviews, contracts, royalty statements relating to the publication of certain works; transcripts, clippings, and email printouts of interviews of Fagin; and various lyrics for songs and sheet music.
    - Publications
      - I'll Be Seeing You, 1973-1984 (Box 17, Folder 663)
      - Rhymes of a Jerk, 1973-1974 (Box 17, Folder 664)
      - Stabs, 1976-1977 (Box 17, Folder 665)
      - Miscellaneous, 1973, undated (Box 17, Folder 666)
    - Interviews
      Arranged in rough chronological order.
      - Contact Magazine, 1972-1973 (Box 17, Folder 667)
      - Ethie Stearns, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 668)
      - Lewis Ellingham, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 669)
      - Daniel Kane, 2001 (Box 17, Folder 670)
      - David Avidan, undated (Box 17, Folder 671)
      - Tobias Premper, 2006 (Box 17, Folder 672)
    - Various lyrics for songs and sheet music, undated (Box 17, Folder 673)
- Professional Papers, 1968-2007; Series III; 1.71
  Arranged into seven subseries: Editorial Files, Teaching Files, Film Files, Art Files, Choreography Files, Journalism Files, and Correspondence and Other Papers.
  - Editorial Files
    - Adventures in Poetry, 1973-2007 (Box 17, Folder 674-678)
    - "Bacedifogu", undated (Box 17, Folder 679)
    - "Cocktail Anthology", undated (Box 17, Folder 680)
    - "Kraus", 1968, 1970 (Box 17, Folder 681)
    - "Lyrical Bullets", undated (Box 17, Folder 682)
    - "Peanut Butter Factory", undated (Box 17, Folder 683-687)
    - Un Poco Loco, 1979 (Box 17, Folder 688)
    - "Sal Mimeo", circa 2002 (Box 17, Folder 689-693)
    - Other
      - Shiny Magazine prospectus, undated (Box 17, Folder 694)
      - Publishers Weekly review of "The Green Lake is Awake: by Joseph Ceravolo, 1994 (Box 17, Folder 695)
      - Notes for proposed "Selected Poems of Clark Coolidge", undated (Box 17, Folder 696)
      - Notes for unpublished anthology of American poetry titled "Big", undated (Box 17, Folder 697)
  - Teaching Files
    - Naropa, 1977-2003 (Box 18, Folder 698-701)
    - New School University, 2003-2006 (Box 18, Folder 702-703)
    - Teachers & Writers Collaborative, 1991-1995 (Box 18, Folder 704)
    - UCLA, undated (Box 18, Folder 705)
    - Miscellaneous, 1984-2006 (Box 18, Folder 706)
  - Film Files
    - "Arrivederci, Budapest", undated (Box 18, Folder 707-708)
    - "Men in Scoring Position", undated (Box 18, Folder 709-713)
    - "Portraits and Home Movies", 1997 (Box 18, Folder 714)
    - "Portraits and Home Movies," Super 8mm motion picture, 1997
      Conditions Governing Access
      Access to original audiovisual recordings is restricted. Consult the Beinecke Library Access Services department for information about reference copies.
    - Other Collaborations with Sam Kashner, undated (Box 18, Folder 715-719)
  - Art Files
    - Magazine collage, undated (Box 18, Folder 720)
    - Collage, "I have forbidden women to sleep with cream", undated (Box 18, Folder 721)
    - Newspaper collage, undated (Box 18, Folder 722)
    - Flyer design by Larry Fagin for Warren Sonbert's film showing, "Carriage Trade", undated (Box 18, Folder 723)
  - Choreography Files
    - Danspace Project, 1977-1998 (Box 18, Folder 724-725)
    - Naropa, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 726)
  - Journalism Files
    - Press packet for Rolling Stone Salvador Dali event, 1971 (Box 18, Folder 727)
    - Article on Laurent de Brunhoff for US magazine, 1987 (Box 18, Folder 728)
  - Correspondence and Other Papers
    - Copies of Outgoing Correspondence
      - Bamberger, Bill, 1993 (Box 18, Folder 729)
      - Chris, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 730)
      - Coolidge, Clark, 2006, undated (Box 18, Folder 731-732)
      - Goodins, Gary, 1979 (Box 18, Folder 733)
      - Hornick, Lita, 1975 (Box 18, Folder 734)
      - Lederer, Kary, 2000 (Box 18, Folder 735)
      - Shambala Publications, regarding Kerouac Reader, 1985 (Box 18, Folder 736)
      - Silliman, Ron, 2006 (Box 18, Folder 737)
    - Curriculum vita and material regarding grants, 1970-1985 (Box 18, Folder 738)
    - Material relating to New York Public Library Exhibition, " A Secret Location on the Lower East Side: Adventures in Writing, 1960-1980", 1997-1998 (Box 18, Folder 739)
    - Material relating to poetry readings, lectures, and publications, 1970-2000 (Box 18, Folder 740-746)
    - Item list of collection contents created by Fagin (Box 19, Folder 747-748)
- Cold Storage (Restricted Fragile)
  - "Portraits and Home Movies," Super 8mm motion picture (Reel 714a) (Box cs)
    Access to original audiovisual recordings (Reel 714a) is restricted. Consult the Beinecke Library Access Services department for information about reference copies.